Jon Kirkpatrick

Senior Software Engineer 3570 SW River Parkway #1105 Portland OR, 97239 503-530-9606 basilieus@gmail.com https://github.com/jk-

About Me

Senior Software Engineer with over ten years of experience and success, leading teams across remote locations in both the development, implementation and maintenance of high growth and high traffic websites. An expert in both the front-end and back-end of development. Highly fluent in many programming languages and an engineer of many talents.

Knowledge & Skills

For specifics or additional technologies & software, please inquire

- + Over 10 years of experience in PHP, Python, JavaScript (Symfony, Flask)
- + Extensive knowledge of MySQL and NoSQL systems (Redis, Memcache, etc)
- + Distributed Systems (Docker, AWS S3, CloudFront, EC2)

- + Expert in GIT version control
- + CI/CD and TDD/BDD development processes (Travis, Jenkins, Pytest, PHPUnit Tests)
- + ETL Pipelines and Microservice communications (Kafka, Zookeeper)
- + RESTful API integrations

Experience

CEO / Owner

Stone Torch (2015-Present) www.stonetorch.com

Stone Torch produces high quality, asymmetrical investment ideas for hedge funds, family offices and professional traders. Stone Torch also offers macroeconomic models and advanced economic forecasting tools deliverable in Excel.

- + Nov of 2015, took a sabbatical from programming to learn new skills and a new profession. Started Stone Torch from scratch.
- + Produced macroeconomic models to generate high quality asymmetrical invest ideas for hedge funds, family offices and professional traders. Primarily Long/Short Equity.
- + Built and maintained company website. Symfony PHP, jQuery, Heroku, MySQL (ClearDB), Redis, Memcached, Amazon Cloudfront and S3, Gulp, NPM, Composer and Raygun for error handling and SendGrid for emails.

- + Integrated Stripe payment processing (Recurring Billing) and custom integrations with Box.com for Excel sheet delivery in the cloud.
- + Integrated SSL and DNS configurations.
- + Integrated company emails using Google's G Suite.
- + Marketed my analysis and ran marketing campaigns on Twitter.

CTO / Senior Software Engineer (Remote)

Chess.com - 2011-2015 (4 years)

www.chess.com

Chess.com is the world's largest online gaming website for chess. With over 25 million members and over 1.5 million games played a day. It's the number one destination for all things chess.

- + Kept the site fast, responsive and alive allowing the site to grow from 200K users to over 20 million.
- + Integration of tech stack and company communications.
- + Finding and hiring new talent and on-boarding new talent. Grew and managed development team from three members to fourteen.
- + Planning, managing and integrating new features and participating in code reviews.
- + Tech Used: Symfony PHP, Angular, Gulp/LessCSS, NPM, Jira, HipChat, GIT/GitHub, Vagrant, AWS S3/CloudFront, Jenkins & CI/CD processes, Nginx, Memcached, MySQL, PHPUnit

Web Development Consultant

Self-employed (2003-2011)

Provided numerous companies with advice, project implementations and training related to web development in e-commerce, gaming, product mapping of vehicle specifications, image processing, billing implementations, performance improvements and scripts that could offload tedious tasks.

Current Projects

Talis – Natural Language Processing (NLP) Twitch Bot

A Microservice NLP Twitch Bot written in Python; utilizing Docker, Kafka and Zookeeper. A bot that can speak like a twitch user and perform numerous tasks such as spam detection and question answering (Wikipedia integration). https://github.com/jk-/talis/tree/master/talis

Education

ITT Technical Institute (Arizona)

Associates of Applied Science in Multimedia - 2003-2005 Degree focused primarily on Flash, Photoshop, PHP and Computer Science